<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ultimate Mini Game</string>

    <string name="Welcome">Welcome to</string>
    <string name="UltimateMiniGame">Ultimate Mini Game!</string>

    <string name="Select">Select a game!</string>

    <string name="War">War</string>
    <string name="ERS">Egyptian Rat Slap</string>
    <string name="Yahtzee">Yahtzee</string>
    <string name="Spoons">Spoons</string>
    <string name="RPS">Rock-Paper-Scissors</string>

    <string name="CurrentTopScore">Current Top Score: </string>

    <string name="PlayWar">Play War</string>
    <string name="PlayYahtzee">Play Yahtzee</string>
    <string name="PlayERS">Play Egyptian Rat Slap</string>
    <string name="PlayRPS">Play Rock Paper Scissors</string>
    <string name="PlaySpoons">Play Spoons</string>

    <!-- ____________________________ -->
    <!--      HOW TO PLAY LABELS      -->
    <!-- ____________________________ -->

    <string name="HowWar">How to play War</string>
    <string name="HowYahtzee">How to play Yahtzee</string>
    <string name="HowERS">How to play ERS</string>
    <string name="HowRPS">How to play Rock Paper Scissor</string>
    <string name="HowSpoons">How to play Spoons</string>

    <!-- ____________________________ -->
    <!--   LABELS FOR GAMES W/ CARDS  -->
    <!-- ____________________________ -->

    <string name="HTP_ThePack">THE PACK:</string>
    <string name="HTP_TheDeal">THE DEAL:</string>
    <string name="HTP_ThePlay">THE PLAY:</string>
    <string name="HTP_TheScore">HOW TO KEEP SCORE:</string>
    
    <!-- __________________________ -->
    <!-- RULES OF EGYPTIAN RAT SLAP -->
    <!-- __________________________ -->

    <string name="HowToPlayERS_ThePackDescript">A standard 52-card deck is used and can include
        Jokers.</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_DealDescript">Deal cards one at a time face down, to each player
        until all the cards have been dealt evenly. Without looking at any of the cards, each player
        squares up their hand into a neat pile in front of them.</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_PlayDescript">Starting to the left of the dealer players pull the top
        card off their pile and place it face-up in the middle. If the card played is a number card,
        the next player puts down a card, too. This continues around the table until somebody puts
        down a face card or an Ace (J, Q, K, or A).When a face card or an ace is played, the next
        person in the sequence must play another face card or an ace in order for play to continue.
        If the next person in the sequence does not play a face card or an ace within their allotted
        chance,the person who played the last face card or an ace wins the round and the whole pile
        goes to them. The winner begins the next round of play. The only thing that overrides the
        face card or an ace rule is the slap rule. The first person to slap the pile of cards when
        the slap rule is put into effect is the winner of that round. If it cannot be determined who
        was the first to slap the pile, the person with the most fingers on top wins.</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_Slap">SLAP RULES:</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_SlapDescript">Double – When two cards of equivalent value are laid
        down consecutively. Ex: 5, 5 Sandwich – When two cards of equivalent value are laid down
        consecutively, but with one card of different value between them. Ex: 5, 7, 5 Top Bottom –
        When the same card as the first card of the set is laid down. Tens – When two cards played
        consecutively (or with a letter card in between) add up to 10. For this rule, an ace counts
        as one. Ex: 3, 7 or A, K, 9 Jokers – When jokers are used in the game, which should be
        determined before game play begins. Anytime someone lays down a joker, the pile can be
        slapped. Four in a row – When four cards with values in consistent ascending or descending
        order is placed. Ex: 5, 6, 7, 8 or Q, K, A, 2 Marriage – When a queen is placed over or
        under a king. Ex: Q, K or K,Q You must add one or two cards to the bottom of the pile if you
        slap the pile when it was not slappable. Continue playing even if you have run out of cards.
        As long as you dont slap at the wrong time, you are still allowed to "slap in" and get
        cards! Everyone should try to stay in the game until you have a single winner who obtains
        all the cards</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_ScoreDescpt">The player, who has all of the cards at the end of the
        game, wins.</string>

    <!-- ____________________________ -->
    <!-- RULES OF ROCK PAPER SCISSORS -->
    <!-- ____________________________ -->
    
    <string name="HTP_Shapes">What are the shapes of Rock Paper Scissors?</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapeRock">Rock</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapeRockDesc">The rock is when you place your hand into a form of a simple
        fist</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapePaper">Paper</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapePaperDesc">The paper is when you place your hand in an outstretched
        position.</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapeScissors">Scissors</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapeScissorsDssc">This is when you hold your fist with your index and middle 
        finger pointing outwards in a V shape.</string>
    <string name="HTP_Why">Why is Rock Paper Scissor Played?</string>
    <string name="HTP_WhyDesc">This game is played by children and adults and is popular all over 
        the world. Apart from being a game played to pass time, the game is usually played in 
        situations where something has to be chosen. It is similar in that way to other games like 
        flipping the coin, throwing dice or drawing straws. There is no room for cheating or for 
        knowing what the other person is going to do so the results are usually very satisfying with 
        no room for fighting or error.</string>
    <string name="HTP_Rules">What are the rules of RPS?</string>
    <string name="HTP_RulesDesc">Although the game has a lot of complexity to it, the rules to play
        it are pretty simple. The game is played where players deliver hand signals that will
        represent the elements of the game; rock, paper and scissors. The outcome of the game is
        determined by 3 simple rules:
    Rock wins against scissors
    Scissors win against paper
    Paper wins against rock</string>
    <string name="HTP_HandSignals">The Hand Signals</string>
    <string name="HTP_HandDesc">In order to ensure fair play, the game signals have been agreed
        upon to ensure the uniformity of delivery every single time. This ensures that there will
        be no room for error and these signals have been approved for all types of recreational and
        professional play. The proper opening move will impact the overall success of the game.
        This means that special attention should be given to the way you move your hand initially
        before you attempt to make any signal so that other players are not aware of your intention.
        When you succeed to do so, you ensure that other players will not be able to make a signal
        that beats yours, at least not on purpose.</string>
    <string name="HTP_RockDesc">The rock is internationally recognized by a closed fist where the
        thumb is not concealed. It is also one of the most popular opening moves and this is why it
        is considered to be one of the most popular hand signals. Most players will view using the
        rock as an opening move to be somehow aggressive but would still use it because it is easy.
        The rock will beat scissors every time but will be beaten by paper.</string>
    <string name="HTP_PaperDesc">Paper is delivered in the same way as the rock except that in this
        case all the fingers and the thumb are extended in a way that they all face the same
        direction. The vertical paper or the handshake is strictly forbidden in tournaments of Rock
        Paper Scissors because it might resemble the scissors which can lead to unnecessary
        confusion. Paper is one of the most challenging opening moves because there is no indication
        of what you intend to do next. As a result, many players will be concerned when you use it
        as an opening move to your game. Paper will beat rock but will be beaten by scissors in no
        time.</string>
    <string name="HTP_ScissorsDesc">Scissors are thrown in the same way as rock where the hand is
        clenched into a fist but the index and the middle finger are extended to the front in order
        to make an angle that is of 30 to 45 degrees in a way that would resemble a pair of scissors
        . The use of horizontal scissors is strictly forbidden in tournaments because they can
        resemble the shape of paper. Opening with scissors is not a very smart move because your
        opponent will be able to guess what your signal is going to be easily and so will be able to
        come up with a stronger signal.</string>
    <string name="HTP_RPSNote">It is very important to conceal your move and to surprise your
        opponent if you want to make sure that you will win this game.</string>

    <!-- __________________________ -->
    <!--        RULES OF WAR        -->
    <!-- __________________________ -->

    <string name="HTPW_Goal">The goal is to be the first player with all 52 cards</string>
    <string name="HTPW_DealDesc">The deck is divided evenly, with each player receiving 26 cards,
        dealt one at a time, face down. Anyone may deal first. Each player places their stack of
        cards face down, in front of them.</string>
    <string name="HTPW_PlayDesc">Each player turns up a card at the same time and the player with
        the higher card takes both cards and puts them, face down, on the bottom of his stack. If
        the cards are the same rank, it is War. Each player turns up one card face down and one card
        face up. The player with the higher cards takes both piles (six cards). If the turned-up
        cards are again the same rank, each player places another card face down and turns another
        card face up. The player with the higher card takes all 10 cards, and so on.</string>
    <string name="HTPW_ScoreDesc">The game ends when one player has won all the cards.</string>

    <!-- __________________________ -->
    <!--     RULES OF SPOONS        -->
    <!-- __________________________ -->

    <string name="HTPS_PackDesc">A standard deck of 52 cards is used plus a number of spoons using 
        one fewer spoon than the number of players playing in the game</string>
    <string name="HTPS_Object">OBJECT OF THE GAME:</string>
    <string name="HTPS_ObjectDesc">Players take turns trying to collect a four-of-a-kind. Once 
        someone does, everyone tries to grab a spoon. Without a spoon, you get a letter. If a 
        player spells “S-P-O-O-N”, they’re out! The last player standing wins!</string>
    <string name="HTPS_DealDesc">Arrange the spoons in a small circle in the center of the table 
        and deal four cards to each player.</string>
    <string name="HTPS_PlayDesc">Each player tries to make four of a kind. The dealer takes a card 
        off the top of the deck to have five cards in their hand, removes one and passes it face 
        down to the left. Each player discards to the person on their left. The last player places 
        their discard into a trash pile. Cards are picked up and passed quickly around the table 
        until someone gets four of a kind and takes a spoon from the center. Once the player with 
        four of a kind takes a spoon, anyone can take a spoon. The player left without a spoon gets 
        a letter. If at any time the draw cards run out, pause to reshuffle the trash pile and keep 
        going.</string>
    <string name="HTPS_ScoreDesc">The winner is the last player remaining. Players move closer to 
        elimination each time they don’t get a spoon and take the next letter in the word S-P-O-O-N. 
        Spell it and you’re out.</string>

    <!-- __________________________ -->
    <!--    RULES OF YAHTZEE        -->
    <!-- __________________________ -->
    
    <string name="HTPY_Standard">Standard Play:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_Objective">Objective of the Game:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_ObjDesc">The object of Yahtzee is to obtain the highest score from throwing
        5 dice. The game consists of 13 rounds. In each round, you roll the dice and then score the
        roll in one of 13 categories. You must score once in each category. The score is determined
        by a different rule for each category. The game ends once all 13 categories have been scored
        .</string>
    <string name="HTPY_Start">Game Start:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_StartDesc">To start with, roll all the dice. After rolling you can either
        score the current roll (see below), or re-roll any or all of the dice. You may only roll the
        dice a total of 3 times. After rolling 3 times you must choose a category to score. You may
        score the dice at any point in the round, i.e. it doesnt have to be after the 3rd roll.
        </string>
    <string name="HTPY_Scoring">Scoring:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_ScoringDesc">To score your combination of 5 dice, you click one of the 13
        boxes, or write it on the scorecard (scoresheet). There are two sections to the score table,
         the Upper Section and the Lower Section. Once a box has been scored, it cannot be scored
        again for the rest of the game (except the Yahtzee category), so choose wisely.</string>
    <string name="HTPY_UppperScoring">Upper Section Scoring:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_UpperDesc">If you score in the upper section of the table, your score is the
        total of the specified die face. So if you roll: 5 _ 2 _ 5 _ 6 _ 5 and score in the Fives
        category, your total for the category would be 15, because there are three fives, which are
        added together. If the One, Three or Four Categories were selected for scoring with this
        roll, you would score a zero. If placed in the Two or Six category, you would score 2 and 6
        respectively. Bonus: If the total of Upper scores is 63 or more, add a bonus of 35.
        Note that 63 is the total of three each of 1s, 2s, 3s, 4s, 5s and 6s. </string>
    <string name="HTPY_LowerScoring">Lower Section Scoring:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_LowerDesc">In the lower scores, you score either a set amount, or zero if you
        dont satisfy the category requirements.</string>
    <string name="HTPY_3and4Kind">3 and 4 of a kind:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_3and4Desc"> For 3 of a kind you must have at least 3 of the same die faces.
        You score the total of all the dice. For 4 of a kind you would need 4 die faces the same.
        </string>
    <string name="HTPY_Straight">Small and Large Straight:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_StraightsDesc">A Straight is a sequence of consecutive die faces, where a
        small straight is 4 consecutive faces, and a large straight 5 consecutive faces. Small
        straights score 30 and a large 40 points. So if you rolled: 2 - 3 - 2 - 5 - 4 you could
        score 30 in small straight or 0 in large straight.</string>
    <string name="HTPY_House">Full House:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_HouseDesc">A Full House is where you have 3 of a kind and 2 of a kind.
        Full houses score 25 points. i.e.: 3 - 3 - 2 - 3 - 2 would score 25 in the Full House
        category.</string>
    <string name="HTPY_FirstY">First Yahtzee:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_FirstYDesc">A Yahtzee is 5 of a kind and scores 50 points, although you may
        elect NOT to score it as a yahtzee, instead choosing to take it as a top row score and
        safegaurd you bonus.</string>
    <string name="HTPY_AdditionalY">Additional Yahtzees:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_AdditionalYDesc">If you roll a second Yahtzee in a game, and you scored your
        first yahtzee in the Yahtzee box, you would score a further bonus 100 points in the yahtzee
        box. You must also put this roll into another category, as follows; -If the corresponding
        Upper section category is not filled then you must score there. ie if you rolled 4 - 4 - 4 -
        4 - 4 and the Fours Category is not filled, you must put the score in the Fours category.
        -If the corresponding Upper section category is filled you may then put the score anywhere
        on the Upper Section (scoring zero). In 3 of a Kind, 4 of a Kind, and Chance categories you
        would score the total of the die faces. For the Small Straight, Large Straight, and Full
        House categories, you would score 30, 40 and 25 points respectively.</string>
    <string name="HTPY_Chance">Chance:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_ChanceDesc">You can roll anything and be able to put it in the Chance
        category. You score the total of the die faces.</string>
    <string name="HTPY_Scratch">Scratch or Dump Scores:</string>
    <string name="HTPY_ScratchDesc">You can score any roll in any category at any time, even if the
        resulting score is zero. Eg, you can take 2-3-3-4-6 in the 5s category. It will score 0.
        This could be used near the end of a game to lose a poor roll against a difficult-to-get
        category that you have failed to fill (eg, long straight or yahtzee).</string>
    <string name="War_Instructions">Flip phone face down or tap the deal button to flip the cards.</string>
    
</resources>
