<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Ultimate Mini Game</string>

    <string name="Welcome">Welcome to</string>
    <string name="UltimateMiniGame">Ultimate Mini Game!</string>

    <string name="Select">Select a game!</string>

    <string name="War">War</string>
    <string name="ERS">Egyptian Rat Slap</string>
    <string name="Yahtzee">Yahtzee</string>
    <string name="Spoons">Spoons</string>
    <string name="RPS">Rock-Paper-Scissors</string>

    <string name="CurrentTopScore">Current Top Score: </string>

    <string name="PlayWar">Play War</string>
    <string name="PlayYahtzee">Play Yahtzee</string>
    <string name="PlayERS">Play Egyptian Rat Slap</string>
    <string name="PlayRPS">Play Rock Paper Scissors</string>
    <string name="PlaySpoons">Play Spoons</string>

    <string name="HowWar">How to play War</string>
    <string name="HowYahtzee">How to play Yahtzee</string>
    <string name="HowERS">How to play ERS</string>
    <string name="HowRPS">How to play Rock Paper Scissor</string>
    <string name="HowSpoons">How to play Spoons</string>


    <string name="HowToPlayERS_ThePack">THE PACK:</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_ThePackDescript">A standard 52-card deck is used and can include Jokers.</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_Deal">THE DEAL:</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_DealDescript">Deal cards one at a time face down, to each player
        until all the cards have been dealt evenly. Without looking at any of the cards, each player
        squares up their hand into a neat pile in front of them.</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_Play">THE PLAY:</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_PlayDescript">Starting to the left of the dealer players pull the top
        card off their pile and place it face-up in the middle. If the card played is a number card,
        the next player puts down a card, too. This continues around the table until somebody puts
        down a face card or an Ace (J, Q, K, or A).When a face card or an ace is played, the next
        person in the sequence must play another face card or an ace in order for play to continue.
        If the next person in the sequence does not play a face card or an ace within their allotted
        chance,the person who played the last face card or an ace wins the round and the whole pile
        goes to them. The winner begins the next round of play. The only thing that overrides the
        face card or an ace rule is the slap rule. The first person to slap the pile of cards when
        the slap rule is put into effect is the winner of that round. If it cannot be determined who
        was the first to slap the pile, the person with the most fingers on top wins.</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_Slap">SLAP RULES:</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_SlapDescript">Double – When two cards of equivalent value are laid
        down consecutively. Ex: 5, 5 Sandwich – When two cards of equivalent value are laid down
        consecutively, but with one card of different value between them. Ex: 5, 7, 5 Top Bottom –
        When the same card as the first card of the set is laid down. Tens – When two cards played
        consecutively (or with a letter card in between) add up to 10. For this rule, an ace counts
        as one. Ex: 3, 7 or A, K, 9 Jokers – When jokers are used in the game, which should be
        determined before game play begins. Anytime someone lays down a joker, the pile can be
        slapped. Four in a row – When four cards with values in consistent ascending or descending
        order is placed. Ex: 5, 6, 7, 8 or Q, K, A, 2 Marriage – When a queen is placed over or
        under a king. Ex: Q, K or K,Q You must add one or two cards to the bottom of the pile if you
        slap the pile when it was not slappable. Continue playing even if you have run out of cards.
        As long as you dont slap at the wrong time, you are still allowed to "slap in" and get
        cards! Everyone should try to stay in the game until you have a single winner who obtains
        all the cards</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_Score">HOW TO KEEP SCORE:</string>
    <string name="HowToPlayERS_ScoreDescpt">The player, who has all of the cards at the end of the game, wins.</string>

    <string name="HTP_Shapes">What are the shapes of Rock Paper Scissors?</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapeRock">Rock</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapeRockDesc">The rock is when you place your hand into a form of a simple
        fist</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapePaper">Paper</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapePaperDesc">The paper is when you place your hand in an outstretched
        position.</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapeScissors">Scissors</string>
    <string name="HTP_ShapeScissorsDssc">This is when you hold your fist with your index and middle 
        finger pointing outwards in a V shape.</string>
    <string name="HTP_Why">Why is Rock Paper Scissor Played?</string>
    <string name="HTP_WhyDesc">This game is played by children and adults and is popular all over 
        the world. Apart from being a game played to pass time, the game is usually played in 
        situations where something has to be chosen. It is similar in that way to other games like 
        flipping the coin, throwing dice or drawing straws. There is no room for cheating or for 
        knowing what the other person is going to do so the results are usually very satisfying with 
        no room for fighting or error.</string>
    <string name="HTP_Rules">What are the rules of RPS?</string>
    <string name="HTP_RulesDesc">Although the game has a lot of complexity to it, the rules to play
        it are pretty simple. The game is played where players deliver hand signals that will
        represent the elements of the game; rock, paper and scissors. The outcome of the game is
        determined by 3 simple rules:
    Rock wins against scissors
    Scissors win against paper
    Paper wins against rock</string>
    <string name="HTP_HandSignals">The Hand Signals</string>
    <string name="HTP_HandDesc">In order to ensure fair play, the game signals have been agreed
        upon to ensure the uniformity of delivery every single time. This ensures that there will
        be no room for error and these signals have been approved for all types of recreational and
        professional play. The proper opening move will impact the overall success of the game.
        This means that special attention should be given to the way you move your hand initially
        before you attempt to make any signal so that other players are not aware of your intention.
        When you succeed to do so, you ensure that other players will not be able to make a signal
        that beats yours, at least not on purpose.</string>
    <string name="HTP_RockDesc">The rock is internationally recognized by a closed fist where the
        thumb is not concealed. It is also one of the most popular opening moves and this is why it
        is considered to be one of the most popular hand signals. Most players will view using the
        rock as an opening move to be somehow aggressive but would still use it because it is easy.
        The rock will beat scissors every time but will be beaten by paper.</string>
    <string name="HTP_PaperDesc">Paper is delivered in the same way as the rock except that in this
        case all the fingers and the thumb are extended in a way that they all face the same
        direction. The vertical paper or the handshake is strictly forbidden in tournaments of Rock
        Paper Scissors because it might resemble the scissors which can lead to unnecessary
        confusion. Paper is one of the most challenging opening moves because there is no indication
        of what you intend to do next. As a result, many players will be concerned when you use it
        as an opening move to your game. Paper will beat rock but will be beaten by scissors in no
        time.</string>
    <string name="HTP_ScissorsDesc">Scissors are thrown in the same way as rock where the hand is
        clenched into a fist but the index and the middle finger are extended to the front in order
        to make an angle that is of 30 to 45 degrees in a way that would resemble a pair of scissors
        . The use of horizontal scissors is strictly forbidden in tournaments because they can
        resemble the shape of paper. Opening with scissors is not a very smart move because your
        opponent will be able to guess what your signal is going to be easily and so will be able to
        come up with a stronger signal.</string>
    <string name="HTP_RPSNote">It is very important to conceal your move and to surprise your
        opponent if you want to make sure that you will win this game.</string>
    <string name="HTP_War">Each player turns up a card at the same time and the player with the higher
        card wins! Flip your phone upside down to turn over the cards.</string>
    <string name="War_Instructions">Flip your phone down to flip card or press the deal button</string>

</resources>
